<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<!DOCTYPE revistas SYSTEM "articulo.dtd">
<articulos>

	<articulo> 
		<título>Difusion-Weighted MRI: from Brownian Motion to HeadNeck Tumor Characterization</título>
		<autores>
			<autor>C. Utrilla Contreras</autor>
			<autor>B. Marín Aguilera</autor>
			<autor>M. Buitrago Sánchez</autor>
			<autor>J. Graessner</autor>
			<autor>PS. García Raya</autor>
		</autores>
		<resumen>This paper describes basic physics as well as clinical applications of diffusion-weighted magnetic resonance
		imaging. This is a technique that provides complementary information to conventional imaging sequences
		and it is applied in the field of oncologic imaging. This paper focuses on its specific application in head and
		neck, mainly in cancer patients, for characterization of primary tumors, and also for monitoring and predicting
		treatment response after chemotherapy or radiation therapy. Last, although diffusion-weighted imaging is shown
		to add value in several areas by being part of the multi-parametric magnetic resonance imaging approach, there
		are some unsolved challenges, which are proposed as future work.</resumen>
		<palabrasClave>
			<palabraClave>Diffusion-weighted Imaging</palabraClave>
			<palabraClave>Magnetic Resonance Imaging</palabraClave> 
			<palabraClave>Oncologic Imaging</palabraClave> 
			<palabraClave>Tumor Characterization</palabraClave> 
		</palabrasClave>
		<nombreRevista>International Journal of Interactive Multimedia and Artifical Intelligence</nombreRevista>
		<volumenRevista>Vol IV</volumenRevista>
		<páginaInicio>6</páginaInicio>
		<páginaFinal>14</páginaFinal>
		<año>1997</año>
	</articulo>

	<articulo> 
		<título>Detection of Lung Nodules on Medical Images by the
		Use of Fractal Segmentation</título>
		<autores>
			<autor>Afsaneh Abdollahzadeh Rezaie</autor>
			<autor> Ali Habiboghl</autor>
		</autores>
		<resumen>In the present paper, a method for the detection of malignant and benign tumors on the CT scan images has
		been proposed. In the proposed method, firstly the area of interest in which the tumor may exist is selected
		on the original image and by the use of image segmentation and determination of the image’s threshold limit,
		the tumor’s area is specified and then edge detection filters are used for detection of the tumor’s edge. After
		detection of area and by calculating the fractal dimensions with less percent of errors and better resolution, the
		areas where contain the tumor are determined. The images used in the proposed method have been extracted
		from cancer imaging archive database that is made available for public. Compared to other methods, our
		proposed method recognizes successfully benign and malignant tumors in all cases that have been clinically
		approved and belong to the database.</resumen>
		<palabrasClave>
			<palabraClave>Segmentation</palabraClave>
			<palabraClave> Lung Cancer</palabraClave> 
			<palabraClave>CT Scan Images</palabraClave> 
			<palabraClave>Fractal Dimensions</palabraClave> 
			<palabraClave>Benign and Malignant Tumors</palabraClave>
		</palabrasClave>
		<nombreRevista>International Journal of Interactive Multimedia and Artifical Intelligence</nombreRevista>
		<volumenRevista>Vol IV</volumenRevista>
		<páginaInicio>15</páginaInicio>
		<páginaFinal>19</páginaFinal>
		<año>2003</año>
	</articulo>

	<articulo> 
		<título>The Combination of Mammography and MRI for Diagnosing Breast Cancer Using Fuzzy NN and SVM</título>
		<autores>
			<autor>Elham Gohariyan</autor>
			<autor> Mansour Esmaeilpour2</autor>
			<autor>Mohammad Mehdi Shirmohammadi2</autor>
		</autores>
		<resumen>Breast cancer is one of the common cancers among women so that early diagnosing of it can effectively
		help its treatment in this study, considering combination of Mammography and MRI pictures, we will try to
		recognize glands in existing pictures which identify all around of gland complete and precisely and separate it
		completely. In this method using artificial intelligence algorithm such as Affine transformation, Gabor filter,
		neural network, and support vector machine, image analysis will be carried out. The accuracy of proposed
		method is 98.14. In this work a special framework is presented which simplifies cancer diagnosis. The algorithm
		of proposed method is tested on z16 images. High speed and lack of human error are the most important factors
		in proposed intelligent system. </resumen>
		<palabrasClave>
			<palabraClave>Breast Cancer</palabraClave>
			<palabraClave>Mammography and MRI Pictures</palabraClave> 
			<palabraClave>Improved Neural Network</palabraClave> 
			<palabraClave>Support Vector Machine</palabraClave> 
			<palabraClave>Affine Transformation</palabraClave> 
		</palabrasClave>
		<nombreRevista>International Journal of Interactive Multimedia and Artifical Intelligence</nombreRevista>
		<volumenRevista>Vol IV</volumenRevista>
		<páginaInicio>20</páginaInicio>
		<páginaFinal>24</páginaFinal>
		<año>1995</año>
	</articulo>
	
	<articulo> 
		<título>Contour Detection of Mammogram Masses Using ChanVese Model and B-Spline Approximation</título>
		<autores>
			<autor>Youssef Ben Youssef</autor>
			<autor>El hassane Abdelmounim</autor>
			<autor>Abdellah Lamnii</autor>
		</autores>
		<resumen>ChanVese model segmentation has been applied for contour detection of mass region in mammogram in
		our previous work. Available information of the desired object contour is used, in this paper, for B-spline
		approximation. The mass region boundary (contour) is thereafter approximated by a B-spline curve. This
		approach allows synthesizing the shape of the suspected mass appearing in the mammogram. Experimental
		results show the accurateness of mass region contour in mammograms using B-spline approximation.</resumen>
		<palabrasClave>
			<palabraClave>B-spline</palabraClave>
			<palabraClave>ChanVese model</palabraClave> 
			<palabraClave>Mammogram</palabraClave> 
			<palabraClave>Segmentation</palabraClave> 
		</palabrasClave>
		<nombreRevista>International Journal of Interactive Multimedia and Artifical Intelligence</nombreRevista>
		<volumenRevista>Vol IV</volumenRevista>
		<páginaInicio>25</páginaInicio>
		<páginaFinal>27</páginaFinal>
		<año>2008</año>
	</articulo>
	
	
	<articulo> 
		<título>Masticatory System Biomechanical Photoelastic
		Simulation fot the Comparison of the Conventional
		and Uni-Lock Systems in Mandibular Osteosynthesis</título>
		<autores>
			<autor>José Luis Cebrián Carretero1</autor>
			<autor> Mansour Esmaeilpour2</autor>
			<autor> María Teresa Carrascal Morillo</autor>
			<autor>Germán Vincent Fraile</autor>
		</autores>
		<resumen>The biomechanical consequences of the interaction between titanium trauma plates and screws and the
		fractured mandible are still a matter of investigation. The mathematical and biomechanical models that have
		been developed show limitations and the experimental studies are not able to reproduce muscle forces and
		internal stress distributions in the bone-implant interface and mandibular structure. In the present article we
		show a static simulator of the masticatory system to demonstrate in epoxy resin mandibular models, by means
		of 3D (three-dimensional) photoelasticity, the stress distribution using different osteosynthesis methods in the
		mandibular angle fractures. The results showed that the simulator and 3D photoelasticity were a useful method
		to study interactions between bone and osteosynthesis materials. The “Lock” systems can be considered the
		most favourable method due to their stress distribution in the epoxy resin mandible. 3D photoelasticity in
		epoxy resin models is a useful method to evaluate stress distribution for biomechanical studies. Regarding
		to mandibular osteosynthesis, “lock” plates offer the most favourable stress distribution due to being less
		aggressive to the bone.</resumen>
		<palabrasClave>
			<palabraClave>3D Photoelasticity</palabraClave>
			<palabraClave>Biomechanical Simulator</palabraClave> 
			<palabraClave>Masticatory System Simulator</palabraClave> 
			<palabraClave>Mandibular Biomechanics</palabraClave> 
			<palabraClave>Mandibular Osteosynthesis</palabraClave> 
		</palabrasClave>
		<nombreRevista>International Journal of Interactive Multimedia and Artifical Intelligence</nombreRevista>
		<volumenRevista>Vol IV</volumenRevista>
		<páginaInicio>28</páginaInicio>
		<páginaFinal>32</páginaFinal>
		<año>2015</año>
	</articulo>

</articulos>